LINDA YANG

2B Computational Math

617-480-9223



xiaoling.yang@uwaterloo.ca



devlinda.com



/in/lindaayangg



lindaayangg

Technical Skills

Languages

Python • Javascript • ¡Query • HTML • CSS • SQL • GraphQL • C

Frameworks & Environments

React.js • Node.js • Django • Magento • DjangoCMS • Android Studio

Technologies

PostgreSQL • MySQL • Git • Linux • Apache • Photoshop • Illustrator

Achievements

"Hack the 6ix Top 10 Finalist"

"Term Dean's Honours List"

"University of Waterloo President's Scholarship"

"Customer Service and Leadership Certification School of Business"

Extracurriculars

- Hackathons
- · University of Waterloo 2018 Orientation Week Leader
- University of Waterloo Data Science Club Member
- · Gymnasics, Fitness, Piano, Cello

Education

Sep. 2017 - PRESENT

UNIVERSITY OF WATERLOO

Candidate for Bachelor of Mathematics, Computational Mathematics Major

SUMMARY_

Front-end developer with profound experience designing and developing 7 Web and Android apps using modern frameworks and libraries. Ability to communicate effectively in a team setting to collaborate in developing and deploying software. Proactive attendee of hackathons and achieved top 10 finalist at Hack the 6ix.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Developer (Co-op)

Formlabs | Somerville, Massachusetts

Jan. 2019 - Apr. 2019

- Developed 5 stateful React components mounted within DjangoCMS plugins with focus on performance and usability
- Designed 5 Diango object-oriented models to persist in PostgreSOL and created controllers to expose them through REST APIs to fulfill front-end customization
- · Wrote Python migration scripts to extract, transform, and load 5 records of data to the new Django platform
- Ported existing JavaScript and JQuery based front-end web modules to React components to meet project scopes
- Built a fast-performing Star Of Dávid plugin using D3.js library with 4 customizable features to compare various resin materials

Web Developer

Sydney R. Stone | Mississauga, Ontario

Jun. 2018 - Aug. 2018

- Visualized and developed a Magento e-commerce website using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and jQuery that generated high traffic and resulted in 21% increase in revenue
- · Created 2 pull requests to fix third party Magento modules associated with coupons
- · Collaborated with back-end developers to implement enhancements using PHP that improved checkout experience speed by 33%
- · Performed quality assurance to discover errors, optimize usability and ensure compliance with project scope and requirements

PROJECTS

Wave (Hack the 6ix Top 10 Finalist) 🏺 🕨



Aug. 2018 - Sep. 2018

- · Built and published a Web and Android application which transfers data via sound wave technology
- Involved in the full software development life cycle including proper analysis, design, implementation, deployment on Google Play
- Developed and implemented UX wireframes and interactive designs for the web application using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and jQuery

BudgetBuddy 🏺



Sep. 2018 - Sep. 2018

- Worked in a team of four to develop an Android application which recommends shopping alternatives to help one to achieve their desired budgets
- · Conceptualized and designed the user interface for activities, fragments and bond data in a dynamic list view
- Extracted 2 images for each recommendation from the Yelp Fusion API to display in a list